자막제작 - ND24 클럽 자막팀
(http://cafe.naver.com/nd24club)
조건부 배포 / 수정금지
배포시 자막 출처를 꼭 밝혀주세요
22세기 여명의 시작 때
AT THE DAWN OF THE
22ND CENTURY
세계는 환경 붕괴의 위기에
놓여 있고
THE WORLD IS ON THE VERGE
OF ENVIRONMENTAL COLLAPSE
인류 생존의 유일한 희망은
MANKIND'S ONLY HOPE
FOR SURVIVAL
8,500만 년 전의 과거에
달려 있다
LIES 85 MILLION YEARS
IN THE PAST
- 아빠 오셨어요
- 그래
- Hey,Dad.
- Hey,buddy.
봉투 속에 뭐예요?
뭔데요?
What's in the bag? What is it?
뭐가 들었는데요?
Come on. What's in the bag?
말도 안 돼
어디서 나셨어요?
No way.
Where'd you get it?
- 뭐가?
- 아빠가 오렌지 가져오셨어요
- Get what?
- Dad scored an orange.
어디서?
No. From where?
오렌지 마지막으로 본 게
언제인지 기억도 안 나
I can't even remember the last time
I saw one of those.
봐 봐, 조이
Hey, l ook, Zoe.
안녕, 조이
제가 까 줄게요
Hey, Zoe. I can peel it for her.
- 오늘 어땠어?
- 당신 보고 싶었지
- How was your day?
- Missed you.
- 당신은?
- 아주 좋았어
- How was yours?
- Great, actually.
폐 질환 환자가
3명 더 왔어
Three more patients
with pulmo-replasia.
한 명은 7살 남자아이였어
One was a
seven-year-old boy.
- 자가 호흡을 거의 못하더라고
- 상황이 점점 안 좋아져
He could hardly breathe on his own.
It's getting worse and worse out there.
수중호흡기도 더는
소용이 없네
Even a rebreather isn't enough anymore.
코에 살짝 묻었네
Got a little on your nose.
괜찮지?
All right, cool, huh?
놈들이 와요
They're coming.
아래층에서 봤어요
I was downstairs and I saw them.
지금 오고 있어요
They're on their way now.
조이, 숨바꼭질 놀이 시간이야
Zoe,baby,it's time
to play hideaway,okay?
이리 와
Okay, come on.
저 안으로 들어가렴
Climb in there for Mommy.
그렇게 하기만 하면 돼
Everything's gonna...
됐다, 사랑한다
Okay, love you.
인구 통제국입니다
Population Control.
위반 가능성을
조사하고 있습니다
You're being investigated
for a possible violation.
아닙니다, 착오가 있었겠죠
Oh, no, there must be some mistake.
저도 경찰이거든요
Uh... I'm a cop, too.
좀 나가 주시죠
집을 수색해야 하니까요
I need you to step outside
so we can search the premises.
좋아, 나가자
Okay, let's go.
어서들 나와
Come on, guys.
괜찮아
It's okay.
그거 조심하세요!
Hey, be careful with that!
잠깐
Hold it!
엄마! 엄마!
Mommy! Mommy!
이리 와
Come on. Come here.
노는 거 아니야, 어서 나와
I'm not playing around. Come on.
딸한테 손대지 마!
Leave her alone!
손대지 말라고!
Don't touch her!
- 여보!
- 아빠!
- Jim!
- Dad!
- 아빠, 안 돼요! / 엄마!
- 물러서!
- No! Dad! / Mommy!
- Stay back!
- 조이! / 아빠!
- 엄마 봐
- Zoe!- Dad!
- Look at Mommy!
그만 해요
Stop! Stop it!
- 아빠, 안 돼요!
- 여보!
- Dad, no!
- Jim!
알았나? 그건 하지 말았어야지
See? Now, you shouldn't
have done that, pal.
골라드 감옥
2년 후
GOLAD PRISON
2 YEARS LATER
섀넌
Shannon.
5분만입니다
You paid for five minutes.
세상에, 짐
Oh, my God, Jim.
- 엘리자베스
- 짐
- Elisabeth.
- Jim...
당신 모습이..
Look at you...
죄수들이니 공기 정화는
필요 없다 그건가요?
Oh, they're just prisoners, so there's
no need to filter the air, is that it?
내 걱정은 마
난 괜찮아
Don't worry about me.
I'm all done, okay?
여기는 무슨 일이야?
What are you doing here?
애들은 잘 있어?
Are the kids all right?
응, 다들 잘 지내
그런데, 짐..
Yeah, they're good, but, oh, Jim...
테라 노바 모집 담당자가
연락을 취해왔어
Um... I've been contacted by the, the
recruitment people for Terra Nova.
테라 노바
Terra Nova.
끝내주는 소식이네
That's incredible news.
언제인데?
When?
10번째 순례단이
다음 주에 출발 예정이야
The Tenth Pilgrimage is
scheduled to leave next week.
세상에, 리즈
당신 가야 해
My God, Liz, you gotta go.
아이들을 데리고 가야지
You gotta take the kids
and you gotta go.
- 짐..
- 새 인생을 살 기회잖아
- Jim...
- It's a chance at a new life.
- 그걸 망치면 안 돼
- 아니, 그게 아니야
- Don't mess it up.
- No, no, you don't understand.
조이는 못 데리고 간대
They're not gonna let me take Zoe.
왜?
Why?
법 집행 중에는
보상해줄 수 없대
They said we can't be
rewarded for breaking the law.
나, 매디, 조쉬 셋이 가거나
아무도 안 가는 거야
So it's... it's me and Maddy
and Josh or it's nothing.
아니, 뭔가 방법이 있을 거야
No.There's, there's, there's
got to be some way around this.
방법이 있어
There is.
시간 됐습니다
누가 와요
Time's up.
Someone's coming.
알았어요
Okay.
짐, 당신 믿고 있을게
Jim, I'm counting on you.
지금 가야 합니다
We need to go now!
알았어요
Okay, all right.
남편한테 이것만 줄게요
Just let me give him this, okay?
부탁이에요
공기 때문에 힘들잖아요
Please? It's the air. It's killing him.
알겠습니다
Fine.
이거 받고, 몸 잘 챙겨
Take that, and take
care of yourself, okay?
알았지?
Okay?
테라 노바, 새로운 세계
Terra Nova, a new world.
모두에게 희망의 상징으로
알려진 이름
A name everyone, everywhere has
come to know as a symbol of hope.
과학자들이 실험으로
예상 못 한 현상을 발견한 지
22 years have passed since scientists first realized
22년의 시간이 지났습니다
their experiments uncovered an unexpected phenomenon.
물리학자들은 이 변칙을
시공간의 균열이라고 규정했습니다
Physicists characterized this anomaly as a
fracture in the fabric of time and space...
아빠 이 기차 타신댔잖아요
He said he'd be on this train.
오실 거야, 매디
목소리 낮춰
He'll be here, Maddy.
Just keep your voice down.
다 계획해 놨으니 걱정 마
I got it all planned out. Don't worry.
1단계, 아빠가 경비가 삼엄한
시설에서 탈옥하는 거고
Yeah, step one: Dad breaks out
of a maximum-security facility.
2단계는 아빠가 경비가 삼엄한
시설로 잠입하는 거고요
Step two: Dad breaks into
a maximum-security facility.
식은 죽 먹기네요
Piece of cake.
다음 분이요
Next in line, please.
엘리자베스 섀넌 박사입니다
Dr. Elisabeth Shannon.
자녀 2명과 함께 가시는 거죠?
Transferring with two children?
그렇습니다
That's right.
지금부터 1시간 후
In just an hour from now,
이 순례단이 테라 노바로 가는
순례민 전부를 데려갈 것입니다
this Pilgrimage will bring
the total number of colonists to Terra Nova to...
사랑해
I love you.
벌써 네가 보고 싶어
I miss you already.
널 거기에 데려갈 방법을
알아낼 거야
I'm gonna figure out a
way to get you there...
내가 다시 돌아와서
데려가야 한데도 말이야
even if I have to come back
here and get you myself.
일방로 여행이잖아, 조쉬
It's a one-way trip, Josh.
돌아올 방법은 없어
There's no way back.
마지막 탑승이 시작됐습니다
Final call has commenced.
즉시 출발 플랫폼으로
가 주시기 바랍니다
Please proceed immediately
to the departure platform.
가서 행복하게 살아
Go. Live a wonderful life.
사랑해
I love you.
수중호흡기를 제공된 통에
반납해 주시기 바랍니다
Please return your rebreathers and
place them in the bins provided.
수중호흡기는 필요하지 않을 겁니다
Your rebreathers will not be required.
3번 보안 출입구
SECURITY GATE 3
출발 플랫폼은
저 통로로 가시면 됩니다
Launch platform is
straight down that corridor.
서두르세요
Hurry.
14번 통로
26-C 문
Corridor 14
Door 26-C
소포 대기 상태
Package is waiting
- 늦었잖아
- 어디 있어?
- You're late.
- Where is it?
돈 먼저 내놔
The money first.
어디 있냐고?
Where is it?
걸리면 난 모르는 일이야
기억해
Remember, if you get caught,
you're on your own.
관문 팽창 카운터 5분 전 시작입니다
Portal dilation will commence in T-minus five...
여보, 어디에 있는 거야?
Come on, Jim, where are you?
아빠가 못 오셔도 가요?
If Dad doesn't make it,
do we still have to go?
아빠 오실 거야
He'll make it.
그래야만 해
He has to.
사상 지평선이
0.6 마이크론입니다
The event horizon is
at point-six microns.
0.7로 유지하라
Point-seven.
Holding at point-seven.
관문 팽창 개시 대기 중
Standing by to initiate portal dilation.
목적지 상황 안정적입니다
Terminus is stable.
관문 팽창 개시하라
Initiate portal dilation.
여러분의 신체는 산소가 풍부한
대기에 익숙하지 않을 것입니다
Your bodies will not be accustomed
to the oxygen-rich atmosphere.
짧고 고르게 호흡하십시오
Please take short, even breaths.
의료팀이 도움을 줄 것입니다
Medical assistance and
care will be on hand.
- 수신 관문이 동기화됐습니다
- 여기 좀 보셔야겠습니다
- Receiving portal is synchronized.
- Sir, you need to have a look at this.
목적지 상황 안정적입니다
Terminus is stable.
경비 불러
Get me security.
이동하는 동안
방향감각을 상실할 수 있습니다
Disorientation is
expected while transiting.
여러분의 눈은 밝은 햇빛에
익숙하지 않을 것입니다
Your eyes will not be accustomed
to the bright sunlight.
의료 지원을 해 드릴 것입니다
Medical care will be on
hand to provide assistance.
아빠 안 오실 거예요
뭔가 잘못됐다고요
I'm telling you, he's not gonna show.
Something went wrong.
엄마
Mom.
짐, 세상에
Oh, Jim, thank God.
- 아빠
- 괜찮아, 진정해
- Dad.
- Okay, okay. Easy.
괜히 소란 피우지 말거라
Don't call attention.
구역 침범이 있었습니다
용의자는..
Perimeter breach. Suspect...
짐, 왜요?
Jim, what?
가방 받아
Take the pack.
무슨 일이 있어도 계속 가
Whatever happens, keep moving.
어서 가
Go. Go.
잠깐 밖으로 나오시죠
Sir, I need you to step out of line.
제한 구역에서 나오는 게
목격됐습니다
You were seen leaving a restricted area.
죄송합니다
길을 잘못 들었어요
Oh, sorry, I took a wrong turn.
- 엄마!
- 계속 가야 해
- Mom!
- We have to keep going.
저기 들어가면
다시 못 돌아오잖아요
If we go in there, we can't come back.
바로 따라갈 거야
We will be right behind you.
어서 가
Go.
이미 경비를 통과했습니다
I've already been through security.
짐을 확인하고
망막 스캔도 해야겠습니다
I need to check your pack
and do a retinal scan.
이미 다 통과했다고
했지 않습니까
I told you I've already been cleared.
아빠 없이는 못 가요
No, I won't go without Dad.
오빠랑 함께 가
Go with your brother.
- 엄마
- 괜찮아
- Mom!
- It's okay.
바로 뒤쫓아 갈 거야, 매디
I'm gonna be right behind you, Maddy.
- 하지만 아빠는..
- 방법을 찾을 거야, 알았어?
- But Dad...
- Will find a way. Okay?
아빠는 항상 그러시잖아
He always does.
이제 가
Now go.
찾으실 거야
He will.
사랑한다
I love you.
이런 게 어디 있습니까
This is ridiculous.
실수하신 게 분명합니다
You must have made a mistake.
왜 제한 구역에 계셨는지
말씀해 주셔야 합니다
Sir, I need to know why you
were in a restricted area.
지금 저랑 같이 가셔야겠습니다
Sir, you're gonna have
to come with me now.
저놈 막아!
Stop that man!
누가 좀 막아!
Someone stop him!
물러서세요!
Back up, back up!
자 다들 가세요
Come on, you guys, let's go.
산소 과다로 쇼크 상태예요!
He's going into hyperoxic shock!
이산화탄소 주입기 주세요!
CO2 infuser now!
- 아빠
- 총이다!
- Dad!
- Gun!
내 가족에게서 떨어져!
Get away from my family!
내려놔, 내려놔!
MAN: Put it down! Put it down!
무기가 더 있는지
가방을 뒤져봐
Check that pack for more weapons!
안 돼! 안 돼!
No! No! No!
Terra Nova
1x01-02 Genesis
ORIGINAL AIR DATE ON FOX
2011/09/27
동영상 정보
HDTV-FQM / 700M
싱크편집
박창균(fasces@paran.com)
박창균(fasces@paran.com
한글번역
강진희(svarb616@naver.com)
전은형(clleox@yahoo.com)
한글번역
맞습니다
You heard right.
밀입국자 2명입니다
성인 남성과 5세 여아입니다
Two stowaways-- adult male
and a five-year-old girl.
알았다, 워싱턴 중위
Copy that, Lieutenant Washington.
테일러 중령님한테
돌아가고 있다고 전해달라
Tell Commander Taylor
we're headed back now.
우리 상황이 얼마나
나쁜 것 같아?
So how much trouble
do you think we're in?
당신은 모집 대상이었잖아
Well, you were recruited.
당신이 정말로 필요하니
봐줄 거야
I mean, they need you too much
not to cut you some slack.
나?
Me?
남은 형량을 채우게 할 것 같아?
You think they'll make
you serve out your time?
아니길 바라야지
I hope not.
앞으로 8,500만 년 후에나
풀려나게 되어 있는데
I'm not scheduled to be released
for another 85 million years.
저거 구름이에요?
Are those clouds?
그래, 아가, 그렇단다
Yeah, sweetie, they are.
너무 하얘요
They're so white.
조이?
Hey, uh, Zoe?
오래 떨어져 있었지만
나 기억하지?
I know I was gone a long time,
but you remember me, right?
알로사우르스가 음파 지뢰를
밟은 모양이야, 계속 가
Allosaur tripped a sonic-mine.
Just keep moving.
알로사우르스면
육식동물이야?
Allosaur-- that the
carnivorous kind?
그래
Yep.
다 왔네
We're getting close.
테라 노바에 잘 왔습니다
Hey, welcome to Terra Nova.
환영합니다
Welcome!
2149년의 시민 여러분
Citizens of 2149...
저는 나다니엘 테일러
중령입니다
I'm Commander Nathaniel Taylor.
다들 이미 알고 계시겠죠
But you probably already know that.
축하합니다
Congratulations.
제가 7년 전 그랬던 것처럼
Each one of you has taken a first step,
여러분은 새로운 시작에
just as I did seven years ago,
방금 첫발을 내딛으셨습니다
toward a new beginning.
우리는 함께
새 문명의 여명에 있습니다
Together, we are at the
dawn of a new civilization.
부담은 없습니다
No pressure.
여러분이 떠나온 세상에서
인간의 기본 본능인
The world you left behind fell victim to
some of the baser instincts of our species:
탐욕, 전쟁, 무지의
희생양이었습니다
greed, war, ignorance.
우리가 망쳤습니다
우리 고향을 파괴했죠
We blew it.
We destroyed our home.
하지만 우리는 두 번째 기회를
부여받았습니다
But we have been entrusted
with a second chance.
새롭게 시작할 기회이자
A chance to start over.
바로 잡을 기회죠
A chance to get it right.
테라 노바에 오신 걸
환영합니다, 여러분
Welcome to Terra Nova, folks.
고향에 잘 오셨습니다
Welcome home.
테일러가 두 분을
보고 싶어합니다
Taylor wants to see you.
두 분만요
Without the children.
알겠습니다
Okay.
금방 올게, 얘들아
We'll be right back, sweetheart.
금방 올 거야
We'll be right back.
엘리자베스 섀넌 박사님
Dr. Elisabeth Shannon.
노스웨스턴 의대 수석이고
First in your class at Northwestern Med.
면역학, 박테리아학이랑
Doctor of science in immunology, bacteriology,
이름도 모르는 분야 박사시군요
and a couple other ologies I can't even pronounce.
빈민병원에서 2년간
무료 외상 진료도 하셨네요
Two years pro bono trauma work
at I Help the Poor People General.
- 테일러 중령님
- 제가 이해가 안 되는 건
- Commander Taylor...
- What I don't get is it also says here
부군이 골라드 감옥에서 현재
6년 형량으로 수감 중이라는 겁니다
that your husband is currently serving
a six-year bit at Golad lock away.
그런데 여기 계시는군요
And yet, here he is.
3번째 자녀분을 데리고요
With a third child in tow.
제가 어떻게 이해해야 합니까?
What am I to make of this?
이건 전부 제 생각이었습니다
Look, uh, this was all my idea, okay?
엘리자베스는 알지도 못했죠
Elisabeth didn't even know.
그렇습니까?
Didn't she?
외부 도움 없이
골라드에서 탈출하지는 못하죠
A man doesn't escape from Golad
without help from the outside.
조이를 데려가지 못하게 했습니다
Um, they weren't going
to let us bring Zoe.
다른 방법이 없었죠
There was no other choice.
아이가 둘 있는
경찰 가족
Law caps families at two kids.
셋째 아이를 낳았고
발각돼서 벌을 받았다
You had a third, you got
caught and you took the fall.
중요한 건 이겁니다
The thing is this:
난 다른 시대 인구 법에는
관심이 없습니다
I really don't care about
populations laws from another time.
그 사람이 여기에서
쓸모가 있느냐에 관심이 있죠
What I do care about is whether or not
an individual is of use to this colony.
우리한테 의사는 필요합니다
A doctor we need.
탈옥한 도망자는
별로 그렇지 않죠
An escaped fugitive--
not so much.
테일러 중령님
저희는 새로 시작만 하면 됩니다
Commander Taylor, all we're looking
for here is... a fresh start.
다시 가족으로
지내고 싶은 것뿐이라고요
We just want to be a family again.
섀넌 박사님
여기 오셔서 기쁩니다
Well, Dr.Shannon, we are
pleased to have you here.
워싱턴 중위가
필요한 장비를 드릴 겁니다
Lieutenant Washington
will show you your kits.
남편분과 단둘이
얘기를 좀 해야겠군요
I'm going to have a private
word with your husband.
수감되기 전에
경찰이었다고 되어 있군요
Now it also says here that you
were a cop before you went away.
- 시카고 경찰 마약 단속반이었죠
- 이해가 안 되는군요
- Narcotics, Chicago P.D.
- I don't understand.
법 수호를 맹세한 사람과
A man sworn to uphold the law,
부인처럼 성공한 사람이
a woman as accomplished as your wife
셋째 아이를 갖기로 하다니요
and you decide to have a third kid.
모든 위험을 감수하고요
왜입니까?
To risk everything. Why?
그 당시에는
좋은 생각 같았죠
It seemed like a good idea at the time.
좋은 생각 같았다고요?
You thought that was a good idea?
걸리지 않을 거라 생각했소?
That you'd actually get away with it?
맙소사, 생각이 있는 겁니까?
Good grief, son, what were you thinking?
나와 아내 사이 일은
당신이 알 바 아니오
What's between me and my wife
is none of your damn business.
이제 날 가두기라도 할 겁니까?
Now, are you going to lock me up or what?
당신을 내쫓고 혼자 알아서
살도록 해야겠소
What I ought to do is throw you outside
the fence and let you fend for yourself.
아니, 나한테 총과 배지를 주고
No, what you ought to do is give me
a gun and a badge
내가 잘하는 일을 하게 하시는 거죠
and let me do what I'm good at.
여기에도 잡아야 할 악당이
있을 거 아닙니까
There must be some bad guys
around here who need catching.
농장 잡업에 한 자리 있소
Agricultural detail is down a man.
가 보시오
That's all.
제 딸이 저는 농사에
절대 어울리지 않는다더군요
According to my daughter, I have whatever
the opposite of a green thumb is.
최선을 다하죠
I'll do my best.
농사일
Agricultural duty.
당신 할 수 있지?
You can make that work, right?
번호판 만드는 거보다 낫지
Beats making license plates.
여러분 집은
새 정착지인 이곳입니다
Your quarters are here in the
newer part of the settlement.
공급품은 저쪽
PX에 있습니다
There's a PX down that way for supplies.
숙소 중 일부는 아직
마무리가 안 됐습니다
Some of these units
aren't quite finished.
여러분 숙소는 아직
페인트칠도 안 되어 있습니다
I don't even think yours
has been painted yet.
여기입니다
Here we are.
우리 집이라고요?
This is ours?
필요한 게 있으시면
말씀하세요
If you need anything, just let us know.
어서 가자
This is it. Come on.
창문 많은 방이 내 방이에요!
I get the room with the most windows!
내가 먼저 골라
I get first pick.
- 누구 맘대로?
- 내가 첫째잖아
- Says who?
- I'm the oldest.
우리한테 M-7 모델을 줬어
Man, they gave us the M-7 model.
나쁘지 않지?
It's not bad, right?
벽에 페인트도 칠하면 되고
We can throw some paint on the walls.
러그 같은 것도 깔고
Get a rug or something.
여기 러그도 있대?
Do they have rugs here?
복도에 공룡 카펫 깔면
멋질지도 몰라
Maybe a nice sort of Dino runner
would be great down the hallway.
글쎄
I don't know.
짐
Jim.
우리 잘한 거 맞지?
We did the right thing, didn't we?
여기 온 거 말이야
Coming here?
엄마, 내 방이 없어요
Mommy, there's no room for me.
방법이 있을 거야, 아가
We'll figure something out, sweetie.
조이가 날 몰라
She doesn't know me.
마지막 봤을 때
막 세 살이었잖아
Last time you saw her,
she was barely three.
누구 침대를 찾아야 하지..
이름이 뭐라고 했지?
So, we need to find a bed for...
Oh, what's your name again?
그래, 마사다
Oh, that's right, Martha.
그러니까..
아, 맞다
Okay, so we need...
Oh, right, right, right.
프리실라야
Priscilla.
프리실라가 아니야?
Not Priscilla, huh?
잠깐, 알겠다
Hmm... Oh, wait, I got it.
조이잖아
It's Zoe. Yeah.
안녕, 조이
난 알프레도야
Well, hi, Zoe. My name's Alfredo.
만나서 반갑다
It's a pleasure to meet you.
왜?
I... What?
아니잖아요
No, it's not.
그럼 뭐야?
Well, what is it?
아빠요
Daddy.
이제 됐어요
Okay, so it's settled.
나랑 조이가 이 방을 쓸게요
더 커 보이니까요
Me and Zoe get this room,
seeing as it's bigger.
다른 침대도 넣을 수 있어
And we can squeeze another bed in.
- 나 봐도 돼?
- 그럼
- Can I see?
- Yeah.
행복한 가족이네요
One big, happy family.
아무 일도 없었던 것 같아요
Like nothing ever happened.
그게 무슨 말이야?
What's that supposed to mean?
아버지가 감옥에 있었으니
우리끼리 힘겹게 살아야 했던
I guess we're supposed to just
forget about the last years
몇 년은 그냥 잊어야
하는 것 같잖아요
we had to fend for ourselves
'cause Dad was in jail.
- 조쉬!
- 그만 해라
- Josh!
- That's enough.
엄마도 인정하세요
다 아빠 잘못이잖아요
Admit it, Mom, it's his own damn fault.
욱해서 그 경찰만
때리지 않았으면
If he hadn't lost his cool
and thrown a punch at that cop
그냥 지나갔을지도
모르는 일이잖아요
he might have just gotten away with a fine.
그 생각은 안 해보셨어요?
Have you ever thought about that?
여기서 과거 얘기로
싸우지는 않을 거야, 알겠어?
Hey, we're not gonna stand here
and argue the past with you, okay?
새로 시작하는 거라고
We're starting over.
한 가족으로 말이야
As a family.
조이? 누구 조이 봤어요?
어디 갔지?
Zoe? Has anybody seen Zoe?
Where did she go?
- 너랑 있는 줄 알았는데
- 그랬었죠
- I thought she was with you.
- She was.
- 조이?
- Zoe?
조이?
Zoe?
조이!
Zoe!
잘 자거라
Good night, sweetheart.
집에 오셔서 너무 좋아요, 아빠
I'm really glad you're home, Dad.
안녕히 주무세요
Good night.
잘 자라
Night.
네
Yep.
조이가 내 방에서
자는데 익숙해졌어
She got used to sleeping in my room.
침대가 모자라는 것 같네
It seems we've run out of beds.
다행히 소파가 있잖아
Luckily there's a couch.
맞아
Right.
답은 그렇다야
The answer is yes.
옳은 일을 한 거야
여기에 온 거
We did do the right thing, coming here.
이게 앞으로 사흘 동안
우리가 먹을 거라고?
You telling me this is all we
can have for the next three days?
안내 책자 안 읽었어?
Did you not read any of
the literature they gave us?
진짜 음식은 모두 효소가 들었는데
우리 몸이 아직 익숙하지 않다고
Real food has all these enzymes
our bodies aren't used to yet.
그리고 그렇게
맛이 없지도 않아
And besides it's really not that bad.
오리엔테이션에
가기 싫어요
I don't want to go to orientation.
엄마랑 있을래요
I want to stay with you.
엄마는 새로 가야 할
직장이 있잖아
Mommy has a brand-new
job she has to go to.
언니 오빠도 갈 테니
And Maddy and Josh are going to go to orientation
함께 가면 돼, 알겠지?
so you can go with them, okay?
온수는 너희가 다 썼구나
You guys used up all the hot water.
고마워
Thanks.
태양 전지가 한 번에
그만큼만 데울 수 있어요
No, the solar panels can only
heat up so much at a time.
하고 싶으면
태양 탓을 하세요
Blame it on the sun, if you want.
농림부가 저쪽으로
400미터 가면 있어요, 아빠
The Agricultural department,
a quarter mile that way, Dad.
- 잠깐, 저쪽?
- 병원은 저기 있어야 해요
- And... Wait, that way?
- The clinic should be right here.
확실하니?
Are you sure?
나 가야겠어
All right, I better go.
알았다
That's... okay.
즐거운 시간 보내
Have a good time.
자, 조이는
혼자 돌아다니면 안 돼, 알았지?
Okay, now, you-- no more
wandering off, okay?
그래
Okay.
- 끝나면 보자
- 네
- So see you when you're done.
- Yeah.
- 재밌게 보내
- 간다
- Have fun.
- Bye.
남쪽 끝에서 만나야 해, 가자
Okay, so we should be meeting at
the south end. Come on.
말도 안 돼
No way.
믿기지가 않아
I can't believe it!
뭐가?
Can't believe what?
그게 뭔데?
What is it?
진짜 몰라?
You've got to be joking.
그 탐사선이잖아
It's the probe.
처음 시간 균열을 발견하고
보냈던 그 탐사선
You know, the one they sent through when
they first discovered the time fracture.
어떻게 그걸 몰라?
How can you not know that?
내 인생 살기도 바빴어, 매디
I was having a life, Maddy.
처음에는 그 틈으로 얼마나 거슬러 가는지
어디로 가는지 아무도 몰랐어
No one knew at first how far back the
fracture went or even where it led to.
무선 송신기를 탑재해서
다시 보냈잖아
They sent this back with a
beacon inside so that, you know,
몇백만 년 이후인지 알아내려고
they could find it however
many millions of years later.
결국은 몰랐지만
Only, they never did.
그래?
Huh?
그래서 새로운 시간 흐름을
어떻게 할지를 알게 됐어
That's how they knew that they
were dealing with a new time stream.
관심 없어, 매디
Whatever, Maddy.
뭐라고? 우리가 같은
시간 흐름에 있지 않으면
Whatever? Okay, Josh, you do realize
that if we were in the same time stream,
마치..
then something like--
아마.. 나비 효과가 일어날 거야
I don't know-- just stepping on a
butterfly could change everything.
예를 들어, 우리가
아예 태어나지 않거나 말이야
Like, for example, us never being born.
다른 사람들처럼
나도 이름 새겨도 돼?
Can I scratch my name on
it like everybody else's?
그래, 해, 조이
Yeah, go ahead, Zoe.
새겨 넣어
Mark it up.
난 갈 거야
Okay, I'm out of here.
어디 가는데?
Where are you going?
진짜 음식 좀 먹으러
배고파 죽겠어
To get some real food. I'm starving.
오리엔테이션은?
What about orientation?
나 혼자 할 거야, 매디
I can explore on my own, Maddy.
- 오빠!
- 조이나 잘 봐
- Josh!
- Look after Zoe.
단순하게 하면 됩니다
Let's keep it simple.
잡초 뽑는 걸
좀 도와주실래요?
Why don't you, uh, give us a
hand with, uh, some weeding?
- 잡초요?
- 네
- Weeding?
- Yeah.
- 할 수 있겠네요
- 좋습니다
- Think I can handle that.
- Good.
네, 여기는 유지할 게
정말 많죠
Yeah, this place needs
a whole lot of upkeep.
맡기고 가겠습니다
I'll leave you to it.
좋아
Okay.
전 괜찮아요
그냥 벌레였어요
I'm okay. I'm okay. Just a bug.
걱정 마세요, 괜찮습니다
No worries. I'm okay.
그냥.. 벌레거든요
Just a... just a bug.
좋았어!
Yes!
고맙습니다
Thanks.
이게 재밌니?
Oh, this is funny to you?
새로 온 사람이 과일 먹으려는 거
놀리는 걸로 시작해?
That's how you get off-- making fun
of the new guy trying to eat fruit?
이리 줘 봐
Here.
Give it to me.
먹어봐
Go ahead.
익숙해질 거야, 장담해
You get used to it. I promise.
그 말 믿을게
I'll take your word for it.
이름이 뭐야?
Hey, what's your name?
조쉬야
Josh.
난 스카이
I'm Skye.
5번째 순례단이야
Fifth Pilgrimage.
넌 모집된 거야, 당첨된 거야?
So you a recruit or lottery?
엄마가 모집되셔서
우리 모두 왔어
Uh, my mom was recruited,
so we all had to come.
대부분은 운이 좋다고 생각하는데
Most people count themselves lucky.
누군가 두고 왔구나
You left somebody behind, huh?
여기서 할 게 뭐가 있어?
So what's there to
do around here anyway?
가장자리까지 얼마나 가깝게
가고 싶느냐에 달렸어
Well, depends on how close
to the edge you like to walk.
- 1번 침상 안정됐고, 상처도 봉합했어요
- 잘하셨어요
- Okay, bed one's sedated and his wound's sutured.
- Great.
간호사님, 여기 좀 와 주세요
Nurse, a hand over here, please.
시간 있으시면 3번 침상
산소 좀 봐주시겠어요?
If you get a sec, could you
check bed three's oxygen?
그럴게요
Okay.
안녕하세요, 섀넌 박사입니다
Hi. I'm Dr. Shannon.
메슥거림과 두통 때문에 오셨군요
Okay, so you came in complaining
of nausea and a headache, right?
다른 의사가 산소 과다라던데요
무슨 소린지는 몰라도요
The other doctor said I was hyperoxic,
whatever that means.
신선한 공기에 익숙하지
않으시단 말입니다
It means you're not used
to so much fresh air.
좀 떼어 주실래요?
Can you unhook me, please?
30분이면 된다던데
이미 지났거든요
They said it'd only take a half hour, and
it's been at least that long already.
정맥 주사는 안 보이는데요
I don't see an IV anywhere.
이런
Whoa!
이런이요?
전문 용어인가요?
"Whoa"? Is that... is
that a technical term?
죄송해요
Sorry.
흥미롭네
Interesting.
혈액에서 과다한 산소를
없애는 게 틀림없구나
They must get rid of the
excess oxygen from the blood.
좀 떼네 주실래요?
Can you just get it off me?
네, 제가..
Yeah. Let me just...
잠시만요
Hang on.
됐어요
There we go.
훨씬 낫네요
All better.
조쉬
Josh.
아빠
Dad.
오리엔테이션에 갔어야 하는데
뭐 하는 거야?
You're supposed to be at orientation.
What are you doing?
조쉬, 첫날을
이렇게 시작하면 되니?
Josh, this is not how
you start your first day.
내 아들을 좀 데려갈게
Would you excuse my son, please?
갈 데가 있거든
There's somewhere he needs to be.
가자, 어서
Let's go. Come on.
내가 말했잖아
Hey, I told you...
사라졌다 갑자기 나타나서
이래라저래라 하지 마세요
You can't just come back after all this time
and start telling me what to do.
가자
Let's go.
2149년 상황은
얼마나 안 좋아?
So how bad are things in 2149?
아는 게 그것뿐일 때는
다 정상 같았는데
It's funny-- when it's the only thing you know,
it all seems so normal,
여기 오니 얼마나 안 좋은지
깨닫게 되니 재밌네
but coming here makes you realize
how bad things have gotten.
그렇게 기억이 많이 나지 않아
I don't really remember much.
떠났을 때 난 어렸거든
I was just a kid when we left.
여기가 내가 지내는 곳이야
Oh, this is my place here.
얘들아
Hey, guys.
얘는 조쉬야
This is Josh.
새로 왔어
He's new.
테라 노바에 온 걸 환영해
난 타샤야
Welcome to Terra Nova.
I'm Tasha.
저긴 헌터고
That's Hunter.
어떠니, 신참?
How you doing, fresh?
지금까지는 좋아
So far, so good.
다들 여기서 지내?
So this is all your guys' place?
응, 우리랑 또 한 명
맥스라고 있어
Yeah, us and one other-- Max.
너희 부모님은?
And your parents?
우리 부모님은 저기 사셔
왜?
Mine live just up that way. Why?
너희 집이잖아
너희는 16살밖에 안 됐고
It's your own place.
Aren't you only, like, 16?
그래서? 우린 일 해
직업이 있어
So? I mean, we work.
We have jobs.
여긴 개척지잖아
빨리 어른이 돼
Yeah, this is the frontier, son.
You got to grow up quick.
그 테일러의 환영 연설은
들었겠네
You got the whole Taylor
welcome speech, didn't you?
문명의 여명에 있다고
We're the new dawn of civilization.
일은 어땠어, 자기야?
How was the office, sweetheart?
나쁘지 않았어
오늘 수력 터빈 하나 완성했지
Not bad. We finished
another hydroturbine today.
신참은 누구야?
Who's the fresh?
조쉬야
Name is Josh.
맥스야, 반가워
Max. Glad to meet you.
날씨 진짜 덥다
OTG에 갈 사람?
It's so hot. Who's up for a little OTG?
- 좋아!
- 걸어서? 꿈도 꾸지 마
- Yes!
- On foot? No way.
이번 주에 부두 일
시작한 게 누구더라?
Well, guess who started
repair dock duty this week.
좋았어, 20분 있다
거기서 보자
Great. Okay. We'll meet you
guys in the usual spot in 20?
- 좋아
- 첫날에 OTG라니
- Yeah.
- OTG on your first day.
기록이 되겠다
That's got to be a record.
우리를 위해
To us.
우리가 진짜 해냈어
We actually made it.
거기서 잠깐 의심했었어
I had my doubts for a minute there.
오늘 어때?
So... how is your day going?
신중세 의학을 좀 펼쳤고
Well, I practiced some neo-medieval medicine,
도둑을 돌봤어
and I tended to a thief.
도둑이라고?
A thief?
그렇게 들었어, 왜?
That's what they told me. Why?
여기서 왜 훔쳐?
Well, it's just, why would
anyone steal anything here?
다들 충분히 제공받잖아
Everyone's pretty much provided for.
누가 알겠어?
하지만 생각해 봐
Who knows? But guess what.
뭘?
What?
당신이 상관할 바 아니야
It's not your problem.
당신 이제 경찰 아니라고
You're not a cop anymore.
조쉬가 오리엔테이션을
안 간 거 말해봐
So what's this about
Josh skipping orientation?
모르겠어
그냥 빼먹었어
I don't know. He just blew it off.
놀랐다는 건 아니야
I mean, I... I can't say I'm surprised.
나도 마찬가지야
Oh, no, I can't say I am, either.
조쉬한테 너무
강압적으로 하면 안 돼
You know what?
We shouldn't be too hard on him.
그동안 많이 힘들었어
He's been through a lot.
우리 다 그래, 그렇다고
나한테 반항해도 되는 건 아니지
We all have. That doesn't excuse
him getting out of line with me.
조쉬가 당신 얼마나
보고 싶어 했는지 알잖아
He really missed
you-- you know that.
그냥 시간을 좀 줘
곧 괜찮아질 거야
Just give him some time, okay?
He'll come around.
그냥 걱정이 돼서 그러는 거야
I just worry about him. That's all.
조쉬가 문제 일으키는 데는
일가견이 있잖아
He has this knack for finding trouble.
어디 가는 거야?
Where are we going?
바짝 따라와
Stay close.
좋아
Okay.
싫으면 안 가도 돼
You... you don't have to come
if you don't want to.
저 밖에? 농담이지?
Out there? You're kidding, right?
알아보려면
같이 가 봐야지
Only way to find out is to come with.
자, 별거 아니야
There.
No big deal.
올 거야, 말 거야?
You coming or not?
스카이, 젠장
Skye. Damn.
어서 와, 너희 없이
가려던 참이야
Come on. We were about
to leave without you.
그랬겠지, 헌터
Ah, hell you were, Hunter.
OTG갈 준비됐어, 신참?
Get ready to go OTG, fresh.
OTG라고?
OTG?
문 바깥이라고
Outside the gates.
나랑 지름길로 갈 사람?
Who's up for the shortcut?
말도 안 돼, 스카이. 거기서 만나
No way,Skye.We'll meet you there.
빨리 와
Keep up.
노력 중이야
I'm trying.
그냥 울음소리야
Just a howler.
생긴 거보다 울음소리가 훨씬 고약하지
Sound a lot worse
than they actually are.
뭐야, 거기 서서 그냥 보기만 할래?
What,are you just going
to stand there and watch?
재밌었지?
You think that was fun?
내가 진짜 끝내주는 거 보여줄까?
You want to see something really cool?
이거보다 더한 거? 그래
Cooler than that? Sure.
좋아. 이리 와
All right. Come on.
이쪽이야
This way.
이거 좀 봐
Check it out.
탐험하다가 발견한 거야
Found it when we were exploring.
저기 더 있어
There's more over there.
뭐야 이게?
What is it?
기하학이나 뭐 그런 종류 같은데
Looks like some kind of
geometry or something.
내 생각엔 공식 같아
확신은 못하겠지만
I think they're equations,
but I can't be sure.
뭐가 뭔지 잘 모르겠어
I-I can't make heads or tails of it.
누가 한 거래?
Who did this?
나도 모르지
I don't know.
왜 이런 바위에다 그랬을까?
Why do it on a bunch of rocks?
전혀 이해가 안 가는데
오래전부터 있던 거 같아
Doesn't make any sense.
It looks like it's been here for awhile.
중령님한테도 말했어?
You tell Taylor about this place?
아니. 사실 우린 여기 있으면 안 돼
No.We're not even
supposed to be out here.
출입금지 구역이거든
This whole area's off-limits.
중령님이 아무도 모르길 바랐나 봐
It's like Taylor doesn't want
anyone to know about this.
그러니까.. 아무한테도 말하지 마, 알았지?
Um... don't tell anybody
about this,all right?
약속이다?
You promise?
좋아
Good.
훔치고 있던 게 뭐기에
총까지 쏜 거예요?
What was he stealing that
made it necessary to shoot him?
전력망을 빼돌리고 있었습니다
Him and his buddies were
siphoning off our power grid.
왜 그래야만 했을까요?
Why would they need to do that?
식서스니까요
They're sixes.
식서스요?
Sixes?
무기를 바닥으로 밀어
Slide your weapon across the floor.
당장!
Now!
기본적으로 칼리소니어스는
정말 까다로운 편입니다
So,basically, Calysonias
is real finicky,
그러니까 질소량을 일정하게 맞추셔야 해요
so you gotta keep the nitrogen level just so,
안 그러면 뿌리가 수산화되거든요
otherwise the roots get hydroxic.
- 수산화라고요?
- 네 / 그렇군요
- Hydroxic?
- Right. / Right.
하실 일은 이걸 식물의 뿌리에 대시고
So what you need to do is you need to
stick this into the root of the plant,
여기에 기록하시면 됩니다
and then you need to record it on here.
알겠습니다
Okay.
듣고 계세요?
Are you listening?
제가 말씀드렸다시피
And like I was saying,
이걸.. 어, 식물에 대고 나서
once you,uh,get it on there,
into the plant, and
여기에 기록하시는 겁니다
then you record it here.
네, 저기 그런데요
금방 올게요
Yeah,you know,I'm gonna be,
I'm gonna be right back,
그러고 나서 계속합시다
and we're gonna do more stuff
with the, with the thing...
- 그러세요
- 수산화죠
- Right.
- Hydroxic.
수산화요
Hydroxic.
희망 플라자에서 다음번엔
백 명 넘게 보내고 싶어하더군
...and Hope Plaza says they want to put
through more than a hundred people next time.
집이 많이 필요할 텐데
시간이 많지 않습니다
That's a lot of housing units,
not a lot of time.
남부 해안의 일을 중지하고
서부 프로젝트에 집중하지
...suspend work on the south beach,
we'll focus on the western project.
중령님, 엎드리세요!
Get down,Taylor!
엎드려요!
Down!
구금실에 처넣어
Throw him in the brig.
나중에 처리할 테니
I'll deal with him later.
그 자식은 대체 누구고 무슨 일이
벌어지는 건지 설명 좀 해주시죠?
You want to tell me who the hell was
and what the hell's going on here?
타게, 함께 산책이나 하지
Come on,let's take a drive.
이곳에 대해 자네가
알아둬야 할 게 많아
There's a lot about this
place you need to know.
학교 좋았어, 그렇지?
School was nice, didn't you think?
놀이터에서 산소호흡기 안 써도 되잖아
You know,playground where you
don't have to wear a rebreather.
- 나 공룡 또 보고 싶어
- 조이..
- I want to see the dinosaurs again.
- Zoe...
그랬구나
You do,huh?
별로 좋은 생각 같진 않은데
It's probably not a good idea,though,
왜냐하면 걔네는 배가 부르면
졸음이 쏟아지게 되는데
'cause if they get too full,
then they get really sleepy and it's really noisy
공룡 코 고는 소리 진짜 시끄럽거든
when dinosaurs snore.
근데 사실 브라키들은 있죠
완전한 초식동물류가 아니라서
Well,actually,brachisauri
aren't actually true herbivores.
가끔 영양보충을 위해
작은 파충류를 먹어요
They,they sometimes supplement
their diets with smaller reptiles,
그래서 앞니들이 한 개씩 더 있는 거예요
which is why they have
proto-lateral incisors.
위아래로요
upper and lower.
그렇군
Okay.
그래, 그럼 나중에 보자
All right,I'll see you guys later.
네
Yeah.
죽고 싶어
Kill me now.
문명을 하루아침에 이룰 순 없지, 섀넌
You can't build civilization
in a day,Shannon.
분명히 방해가 있게 마련이야
Bound to be a few setbacks.
서로 공유를 하고 있었던 거네
We've had our share.
그래요? 뭘 말입니까?
Yeah?Like what?
날 쏘려고 했던 그 친구 있지?
That fella who tried
to put a bullet in me?
테라 노바로부터 분리된 집단의 일원이야
He's part of another settlement
that split away from Terra Nova.
여기에선 그들을 "식서스"라고 부르네
Around here, people call 'em "Sixers."
그들 모두가 여섯 번째
순례단으로 왔기 때문이지
They call them that 'cause they all
came through on the Sixth Pilgrimage.
처음엔 우리와 같아 보였어
At first,they seemed
just like the rest of us.
하지만 곧 수상한 점들이 보이더군
But pretty soon,we began
noticing some things,
캠프 보안절차에 유달리
관심을 보이던 점이랄까
like how curious they were
about camp security procedures.
그때 밀수무기 은닉처를 발견했지
By the time we found the cache of contraband weapons,
계획이 있었다는 것이 드러난 거야
it was clear-- they had an agenda.
무슨 계획이요? 누가 보낸 거죠?
What agenda? Who sent them?
나도 그 부분에 대해
몇 날 며칠을 생각했네
Believe me,many nights,
I've asked myself the same thing.
짧게 말하자면
방심하는 사이에 숨어들었고
Long story short-- they caught
on that we caught on to them,
밤도둑처럼 달아난 거지
then they high-tailed it
like thieves in the night.
중요한 장비와 무기를
도둑질해서 말이야
Pilfered a significant amount
of equipment-- and weapons.
어쩌면 도박을 했던 것일 수도 있겠죠
Well,maybe they gamed
the lottery somehow.
그런 생각도 해봤네
The thought has occurred to me.
희망 플라자는 뭐라고 하던가요?
What did Hope Plaza have
to say about all this?
내가 물어봤을 거라고 생각하나?
What makes you think I asked them?
누가 그들을 보냈고
이유를 알기 전까진
Until we know who sent
those people back,and why,
내가 누굴 믿어야 할지도 모르겠네
I just don't know who in
the future I can trust.
이걸 위해 우리가 싸우는 걸세, 짐
This is what we're fighting for,Jim,
우리 모두를 위한 새로운 시작
a new beginning for all of us.
오늘 일이 보여주더군
If today has shown me anything,
자네가 오늘 취한 행동은
it's shown me that you've got
what it takes to
테라 노바의 보안팀에 합류하기에 적절했네
be part of my security team here in Terra Nova.
배지와 총을 달라고 했었지
You asked me for a badge and a gun.
원한다면 주지
They're yours if you want 'em.
팀의 합류를 환영하네, 섀넌
Welcome aboard,Shannon.
저게 뭐지?
What is it?
어디요?
Where?
중령이다
Taylor to base.
몇몇 차량의 진입을 포착했다
Got a pair of transports in-bound.
매우 빠르게 돌진한다
And they're coming in hot.
- 누굽니까?
- 식서스야
- Who are they?
- Sixers.
상황이 험악해지겠는걸
Things are about to get ugly.
중령이다
I' Taylor to base.
식서스가 시야에 들어왔나?
You got a visual on those Sixers?
포착했습니다만
출입구 밖에 작업반이 있습니다
We seen 'em,but we got a
work crew outside the gates.
데려올 시간이 필요합니다
We need time to get them inside.
시간을 벌어보지
최대한 빨리 들여보내도록
I'll try and slow 'em down, but get
everybody inside as soon as you can.
저깁니다! 두 시 방향!
Over there! Two o'clock!
조심하세요!
Look out!
어디에 쏘고 있는 겁니까?
What are they firing at?
우리를 쏘지 않는데요
'Cause it's not us
저게 대체 뭡니까?
What the hell is that?
카르노타우르스
난 카르노타우르스가 정말 싫은데
Carnotaurus. I hate Carnotaurus.
처치했습니다!
We're all clear!
무슨 일이 벌어진 거지?
What's going on back there?
그냥 운전이나 하십쇼!
Just keep driving!
상황이 바뀌었다. 카르노가 나타났어
Situation's changed.We've
got Carnos out here.
모두 들여보네
식서스는 나중에 상대하지
Get everyone inside.
We'll deal with the Sixers later.
거의 다 됐습니다
조금만 더 끄세요
We're almost there, but
you gotta buy us more time.
이봐! 사람들 가까이 못 오게 해!
Hey! Keep those people back!
식서스가 오고 있다!
We got Sixers coming in!
- 운전대 잡아
- 뭐라고요?
- Take the wheel.
- What?!
- 운전대 잡으라고!
- 네, 알겠습니다
- Take the wheel!
- Okay. Okay.
여기 봐, 이 개자식아!
이쪽이다!
Look at me,you ol' bastard! This way!
엄마! 무슨 일이에요?
Mom!What's happening?
이리 와! 여기 숨어!
Come here!Stay down!
이리 와, 이쪽으로
Come on.Come on.
대체 뭘 기다리나?
What are you waiting for?
소닉스, 발사!
Sonics,go!
뒤로 물러서!
Back away!Get back!
반가워, 테일러
Hello,Taylor.
여기서 뭐 하는 거지, 미라?
What are you doing here,Mira?
동료대접을 이렇게 하면 안 되지
This is no way to treat company.
부하들의 무기를 내리게 해
Have your men lower their weapons.
당신 먼저
You first.
그쪽 수가 더 많아
You're outnumbered.
그럼 뭐가 그리 두려우신가?
Then what are you so afraid of?
이유가 있어서 왔군
Came here for a reason.
우리 사람 하나를 잡고 있잖아
You've got one of my people.
카터는 총에 맞았어
Carter got shot...
우리 전력망을 훔치다가 말이지
while he was
trying to siphon power off our grid.
그가 구금실에 갇혀 있는 걸 알아
We know he's alive and in your brig.
어떻게 알고 있지?
You know this how?
테라 노바에 아직 친구들이 있나 보지
Maybe we still have a few
friends here in Terra Nova.
카터와 마주 앉아서..
Well,maybe I'll have a
sit-down with Carter...
친구들에 대해 대화를 좀 해봐야겠군
...have a little chat
about your friends.
카터를 내놔, 이 개자식아!
We want Carter, you son of a bitch!
- 무기를 당장 내려놔!
- 웃기는 소리 하지 마!
- Put the weapon down now!
- Don't even think about it!
한 발짝도 더 오지 마!
Back up... right there!
조심해, 너!
Watch it,you!
- 물러나!
- 가까이 오지 마!
- Get back!
- Don't come any closer!
그만!
Enough!
물러나!
Stand down!
거래야
A trade.
저게 뭐죠?
What is that?
운석이야
Meteoric iron.
저들이 채석장을 장악했거든
They control the quarry.
카터와 의약품, 탄약을 원해
I want Carter, medical
supplies and ammo.
당신 부하를 돌려주지
You can have your man.
의약품도 주겠어. 탄약은 안 돼
You can have the meds. No ammo.
절대로
No way.
시도해 봤을 뿐이야
Can't blame a girl for trying.
거즈만, 카터를 꺼내와
Guzman,get Carter out of the brig.
의약품도 좀 챙겨오고
Have Medical put together some supplies.
처음 보는데
You're new.
낙원에 온 걸 환영한다
Welcome to Paradise.
- 아빠!
- 다들 괜찮아?
- Dad!
- Are you guys okay?
그래
Yeah.
어떻게 저기에 있게 된 거야?
How'd you get yourself caught
up in the middle of all that?
중령님이 보안팀에 합류해 달래
Taylor asked me to join Security.
다시 경찰이 되는 거네?
So you're going to be a cop again?
섀넌 박사
Dr. Shannon.
의무실에 손이 필요합니다
Uh,we could use a hand
over in the infirmary.
괜찮아, 가
It's all right. Go.
내가 애들 집으로 데리고 갈게
I'll take the girls back to the house.
가자. 괜찮아
Come on. It's okay.
별로 착한 공룡은 아니었어
That wasn't a very nice dinosaur.
그래, 아니었어, 그렇지?
No,he wasn't,was he?
다시 돌아올까?
Is he gonna come back?
걱정할 필요 없어, 알겠니?
Look,you don't have to
worry about him,okay?
여긴 안전해
You're safe here.
집에 가고 싶어
I want to go home.
오, 집에 가고 싶단 말이지?
Oh,you want to go home,huh?
무슨 말인지 알겠어
Uh-huh,I know what you mean.
햇빛 때문에 그러는 거지?
It's all this sunshine, isn't it?
너무 밝잖아
It's way too bright.
그리고 공기도 너무 맑고?
And the,and the fresh air?
이런 것들이 내 신경을 자극하다니
Boy,does that ever get on my nerves.
여기 이 꽃들은 뭐야, 대체?
What's with all these flowers here?
너무 알록달록하잖아
I mean,there's, there's too much color.
- 온 사방에 향기가 진동하네!
- 아빠!
- And they're smelling up the place!
- Daddy!
이리 와. 여기가 집이야, 아가야
Come on. You are home,sweetie.
우리 모두의
We all are.
내가 말했잖아, 스카이
I'm telling you,Skye.
거의 다 왔어 맥스, 믿어봐
We're close,Max,trust me.
매번 온다고 한 것 같은데
I thought you said you
came out here all the time.
그랬는데, 일주일쯤 됐거든
Yeah,well,it's been over a week.
정글은 빨리 자라잖아
And the jungle grows fast.
- 오, 그러셔
- 여기야
- Oh,yeah.
- Here.
찾았다
Here we go.
어떻게 해야 해?
How'd we do?
며칠 더 두는 게 좋을 것 같지만..
나쁘진 않아
Could've used a couple more days,
maybe,but... it's not bad.
여기
Hey.
맛 좀 봐
Have a taste.
그래, 밀주야
Yeah,that is moonshine.
백악기 시대 스타일이지
Cretaceous-style.
뭐로 만든 거야?
What's it made from?
음.. 우린 프럿이라고 불러
Uh... we call 'em fruts.
있지, 프루트와 넛의 합성어야
You know,as in part-fruit,part-nut.
좀 더 채워넣어야 할 것 같아
Looks like we need a... a restock.
새 과일 좀 구해다 줄래?
Well,why don't you guys
go grab us some fresh ones?
- 조쉬하고 나는 자르고 있을게
- 가자
- Then Josh and I'll start cutting.
- Let's do that.
왜 의약품을 주시는 거죠?
Why give Mira the meds?
저들을 이기기 더 힘들게 하시는 겁니다
All we're doing is making it
more difficult to beat them.
거즈, 우리는 광석이 필요하네
알고 있잖나
Look,Guz, we need the ore.
You know that.
박사! 동생제는 그만하면 충분하오
Doc! That's enough iso-biotics.
우리 물자가 부족하면 안 되니까
I don't want us to run short.
아까 일어났던 일
엮이게 해서 미안합니다
Look,I'm sorry you got tangled
up in that situation before.
보안팀이 죄수들에게 좀 더
주의를 기울였어야 하는데
Security should've been more
careful with the prisoner.
환자가 칼을 들이댄 게
처음은 아니었어요
Wouldn't be the first time
a patient's pulled a knife on me.
주립병원에서 오래 일하셨으니
상상이 가오
Considering you put in time at
a state hospital,I expect so.
섀넌 박사, 궁금한 게 있소
Dr.Shannon, I'm curious.
당신 경력이나 이제껏 이룬 성공을 보면..
With your rsum, as accomplished as you are...
거기에서도 잘 살 수 있었을 텐데
you could've had it pretty good back there.
내 말은, 돈도 있고 인맥도 있으니
I mean,money and connections,
괜찮은 삶을 살 수 있었을 거요
you can buy a pretty good life.
저택이라도 살 수 있었을 테고
Maybe even one of those
houses in one of the Domes.
그런데도 당신은 이곳을 택했소
이유가 뭡니까?
Still,you chose to come here. Why?
맞아요. 수없이 많은 동료들이
그 길을 택했어요
Well,yeah,believe me, I've had plenty of
colleagues who have gone down that route,
죽어가는 세상에서
할 수 있는 일을 하며 버텼죠
eking what they can from
a world that's on its last breath.
우리 아이들까지
그렇게 살길 바라지 않았어요
But I didn't want that for my children.
여기에서의 삶은 도전 그 자체겠죠
전혀 과장이 아닐 거예요, 하지만..
I mean,I know life here is gonna present
a lot of challenges to say the least,but...
진실한 무언가의 일부분이 될
자격이 있다고 생각해요
I think they deserve the chance
to be part of something real...
뭔가 새롭고.. 뭔가 미래가 있는 거요
something new... something
that has a future.
이해합니다
I understand.
그래서 나도 내 아들을 이리로 데려왔소
I felt the same way about
getting my own boy here.
아들이 있으신 줄은 몰랐어요
I didn't know you had a son.
두 번째 순례단으로 왔죠
Came in on the Second Pilgrimage.
바로 이 과학부에서 일했었소
Worked right here in the Science division.
몇 년 전에 실종됐소
He went missing a few years back.
유감이에요
I'm so sorry.
아, 아직 희망은 있습니다
Ah,there's always the hope.
난 아들을 포기하지 않았으니까
I haven't given up on him.
섀넌 박사, 당신이 와줘서 기쁩니다
Dr. Shannon, it's good to have you here.
다 잘할 수 있을 거요
I think you're gonna do just fine.
부탁 하나만 드리고 싶은데..
Can I just ask you to please...
남편한테 신경 좀 써주시겠어요?
to be careful with my husband?
보안팀에 합류해 달라고 하셨던 건
You asking him to be on your Security team,
두 분 사이의 일이지만
that is between you and him.
밤에 잠 못 자고 기다리는 건
저니까요
But,you know,I'm the one
who stays up late worrying.
집에 돌아오도록 내가 보장하겠소
I'll make sure he gets home to you.
이게 뭐야?
What is this?
어, 그게, 슬래셔의 꼬리 미늘이야
Oh,it's the,uh,the barb
from a slasher tail.
수컷들한텐 다 있어
The males all have 'em.
- 날카롭네
- 응
- It's sharp.
- Yeah.
네가 걔네 이빨을 한 번 봐야 해
You should see their teeth.
걱정 마. 걔넨 주로 밤에 사냥하니까
Don't worry. They mostly hunt at night.
그렇군. 주로?
Yeah. Mostly?
안 마실래
Oh,no,thanks.
있잖아, 그때 일은 미안하게 생각해
Hey,uh,I'm sorry about
what happened back there.
우리 아빠랑 있었던 일 말이야
That whole thing with my dad.
둘이 사이가 안 좋아?
You two don't get along?
아, 우린 단지..
너무 다른 것뿐이야
Ah,we're just... really
different,that's all.
내 말은, 아빤 완전히 예외없는 사람이야
I mean,he can go from zero
to infinity in no second flat.
아빠가 얼마나 꼬였는지 너도 봤잖아
You saw how bent out of shape he got.
"첫날을 이렇게 시작하면 안 되지, 조쉬"
"This is not how you
start your first day,Josh."
"미안, 아가씨
내 아들은 갈 데가 좀 있단다"
"Oh,excuse me,miss,
my son has somewhere to be."
나한테 규칙을 가르치시겠다?
He's lecturing me about rules?
아빠는 여기 오려고
법이란 법은 다 깼으면서
He broke every rule in the book just to get here.
그래. 너희 아빤 새로운 곳에 나타나서는
이러실 분이구나
Right. No,he's like the kind of guy who
would show up in a new place, and he's like,
"오리엔테이션 빠지고
잘 모르는 사람들이랑 수영이나 가야지"
"Oh,I'm gonna ditch orientation and go for
a swim with a bunch of people I barely know.
맞지?
Right?
그래, 너 아빠랑 정말 다르다
Yeah,you guys are pretty different.
정말 달라
Pretty different.
또 피를 흘리잖아. 어디 좀 봐
You're bleeding again. Let me see.
우리가 계획한 대로
일이 잘 안 된 거 알아
Look,I know things haven't
gone exactly like we planned.
모든 게 바뀔 때야
It's all about to change.
델타 1, 들리나?
Delta One,can you read me?
- 델타 1, 들리는가?
- 듣고 있다, 델타 2
- Delta One,can you read me?
- Go ahead,Delta Two.
빈 테라 노바 수송차량을 발견했다
괜찮아 보인다
We spotted a vacated TN transport. Looks ripe.
전원공급장치와
보이는 탄약은 다 챙겨
Grab the power supplies
and any ammo you find.
빨리 움직여, 멀리 있진 않을 거야
But move fast; they can't be too far.
배터리가 꽉 물렸어
This power cell is jammed.
서둘러야겠어
Hurry it up already.
무슨 일이야?
What's with you?
뭔가 들은 것 같아
Thought I heard something.
넌 항상 뭘 듣잖아
You're always hearing things.
됐다
Got it.
여기서 나가자
Let's get out of here.
뭐였어?
What was that?
울음소리겠지 뭐
Probably just a howler.
그래. 울음소리야
Yeah. A... howler.
날이 저물어 간다
우리 이제 가야 해
You know,it's getting late.
We should go.
찾으셨습니까?
You wanted to see me?
섀넌, 들어오게
Shannon,come on in.
여기 문제가 발생했네
We've got a situation here.
우리 차량 한 대가 없어졌어
One of our rovers went missing.
감시 카메라에 찍혔더군
Surveillance picked this up.
우리 아이들이 구역 밖으로 몰래 나갔어
Couple of our kids sneaking
outside the perimeter.
조쉬!
Josh!
30분 정도 무전 연락을 시도했습니다
We've been trying to reach the rover
over the comm for the last half hour
- 응답이 없습니다
- 밤이 되고 있네
- no response.
- Night is falling.
우리가 아이들을 빨리 데려오지 않으면
다른 게 데려갈지도 몰라
If we don't get to them pretty quick,
something else might.
도대체 얘는 왜 이런 건데?
Why in heaven's name would
he do something like that?
여자애가 끌어들였겠지
She must've talked him into it,
내가 수색대와 함께 가기로 했어
so I'm going to go
with the search party.
여자애? 무슨 여자애?
She? Who's she?
오리엔테이션 빠졌을 때
만난 여자애 있잖아
That girl he met when
he skipped orientation.
돌아가라고 했는데
말을 안 들은 거지
I told him to go back,
but he wouldn't listen.
좋아, 나도 같이 갈래
Okay,I'm going with you.
안 돼, 너무 위험하다고
Uh,no,you're not; it's too dangerous.
- 짐, 우리 아들이 저기 있어!
- 그래, 나한테 맡겨
- Jim,our son is out there!
- Yeah. Let me handle it!
싫어. 당신의 그 "맡겨" 때문에
애가 애초에 저기 있게 된 거야
No,You "handling it" is why he's
out there in the first place.
엘리자베스!
Elisabeth!
여기 있거라
Stay here.
- 동생 잘 보고 있어
- 아빠!
- Watch your sister.
- Dad!
괜찮아. 다 괜찮을 거다
It's okay. Everything's gonna be okay.
약속하마
I promise.
- 젠장!
- 없어졌어
- Damn it!
- It's stripped.
배터리가 없어졌다고
The power cells are gone.
차가 작동을 안 해
The transport's dead.
좋아, 그럼 도움을 요청해야지
Okay,well,then we have to call somebody.
우리가 여기 있는 걸 알려야 하잖아
We have to tell them
that we're out here.
얘 말 못 들었어?
배터리가 없다잖아
Did you hear what he said? It's dead.
그럼 무전기도 안 되는 거야
That means there is no radio.
걸어가기엔 너무 멀어
어두워지기 전에 절대 못 들어갈 거야
It's too far to walk.
We'll never make it back before dark.
오, 세상에. 저게 뭐야?
Oh,God.What's that?
식서스 차량이잖아
That's a Sixer vehicle.
식서스가 뭔데?
What's a Sixer?
- 잠깐, 어디 가는 거야?
- 우리 물건 가지러
- Wait,where are you going?
- To get our stuff back.
스카이, 안 돼!
난 안 갈 거야
Skye,no! I'm not going over there.
식서스는 믿을 수 없다고
You can't trust a Sixer.
상관없어, 태쉬
내가 알아서 할게
Whatever,Tash. I'll handle them.
저기요?
Hello?
우리 비무장이에요. 얘기 좀 해요
We're not armed. We just want to talk
그 배터리 없인
우리 여기서 못 나가요
Hey,we're stuck out here
without those power cells.
스카이
Skye.
- 봐, 피야
- 애들아, 찾았어
- Look,blood.
- Yo,guys,I got them.
배터리 다 여다
The cells are all here.
슬래셔다, 뛰어!
Slasher,run!
빨리, 빨리, 빨리, 빨리!
Go, go,go,go,go,go!Go,go,go!
- 뭐였다고? 슬래셔!
- 그냥 뛰어!
- What is it?! Slasher!
- Just run!
가까이 오지 마!
Get away from me!
이봐요, 진정하고 들어가게 해줘요
Come on,man, let us in,please.
나 당신 기억해요
드레이크 맞죠?
Hey,uh,I remember you. Drake,right?
나예요, 스카이
It's me,Skye.
스카이
Skye.
좋아
All right.
- 들어와
- 빨리 타
- Get in.
- Come on,go.
타, 타! 빨리. 빨리 타!
Get in,get in. Let's go. Get in!
어서! 서둘러!
Come on,go! Hurry!
맥스, 시동 좀 걸어봐!
Max,get this thing started!
알파숫자키 천공기 암호야
(종이카드 매체에 구멍을 내서 판독하는 장치)
Yeah,well,it's got an
alpha-num key-punch.
코드를 모르면..
So unless I know the code,then...
- 그럼, 밑판 열고 잭으로 걸면 되잖아
- 안 돼
- Okay,pop the panel, jack the starter.
- I can't.
부비트랩이 연결돼 있어
The rig is booby-trapped.
이봐요, 드레이크
Hey,Drake.
- 이거 시동 어떻게 걸어요?
- 전원이 나갔어
- Hey,how do you get this thing started?
- It's dead.
슬래셔가 꼬리로 전원변환기를 부쉈거든
Power converter got
crushed by a Slasher tail.
오, 맙소사!
Oh,my God!
피를 너무 많이 흘리고 있어
He's really bleeding a lot.
너네 엄마가 의사랬지, 응?
Hey,your mom's a doctor,right?
여기 무기가 있어!
Found weapons!
이걸로 허벅지 상처 부위 위를 꽉 조여
Tie this around his leg above
the wound tight as you can.
이번에 잘 버티면
넌 더는 신참이 아니야
You make it through this,
you won't be a fresh anymore.
오, 하느님!
Oh,my God!
마지막으로 확인된 위치는 외곽으로
Last known location is the outer marker,
남동쪽 2km 아래였어
two klicks down the southeast road.
그쪽으로 향해가면서
열 탐지기를 작동시키도록
We're gonna head in that direction,
start scanning for a heat signature.
헌터 보이스가 없습니다
Hunter Boyce is missing.
맥스 포프도요
Max Pope,too.
- 그리고 하나 더
- 누군가?
- And another one.
- Who?
제 딸이요
My daughter.
타샤
Tasha.
무기와 탄약을 차에 실어
Weapons and ammo in the vehicle.
- 위생병이 필요하실 거예요
- 아니
- You'll need a medic.
- No.
이 위험한 상황에
부모가 모두 갈 순 없소
Both parents, dangerous situation,bad idea.
- 미안, 짐
- 아니, 난 갈 거야
- Sorry,Jim.
- No,I'm going.
따질 시간 없으니
둘 다 같이 갑시다
No time for squabbles.
Both of you ride with me!
움직여, 제군들!
Move out,people!
사람들 대부분 내가 처음으로
관문을 통과한 걸 알고 있소
Most people know I was the
first man through the portal.
사람들이 모르는 건
나를 따라오던 사람들이오
What people don't know is that
the men who came through behind me,
그들은 관문 밖으로 바로
나타나지 않았었으니까
well,they didn't show up
on this end right away.
눈 깜빡할 시간에 통과했다던데
For them, it was just
the blink of an eye.
난, 118일을 기다렸어요
For me,118 days.
아들에게 무슨 일이 있을까
두려운 거 압니다
Look,I know you're scared for your boy.
당연한 일이죠
하지만 내 요점은
You have every reason
to be. But point is,
이 정글에서 살아남을 수 있다는 거요
this jungle can be survived.
왜 계속 저런 소리를 내는 거야?
Why does it keep making that sound?
오, 맙소사, 저기 하나 더 있어!
Oh,God, there's another one!
슬래터는 떼로 사냥해
Slashers hunt in packs.
사냥감을 코너에 몰아넣고
신호를 보내서 부르지
They corner their prey
and signal the others.
눈 깜짝할 사이에 12마리는 될 거야
Before long,there'll be dozens.
- 우린 여기 갇힌 거야
- 갇힌 거라고, 알아?
- We're stuck in here!
- We're trapped,okay?!
무전기는? 변환기 없이
작동되게 할 수 없어요?
What about the radio?
Can we get it to work without the converter?
아마 안 될 거야
The comm won't work.
하지만 알바레즈가 가방에
휴대용을 넣어뒀을지도 몰라
But Alvarez might have a
portable one in his pack.
- 바닥에 있어
- 헌터, 꺼내봐
- On the floor.
- Hunter,get it out.
그 가방에 있대
It's in that bag.
찾았다
Got it.
누구 안 들려요?
Anybody can hear this?
응답바람. 테라 노바, 응답바람
Come in. Terra Nova,come in.
- 빙빙 돌고만 있잖아요
- 수색망을 구축하는 거요
- We're going in circles.
- No,we're establishing a search grid.
만약 애들이 수색망 밖에 있으면요?
Well,what if they're outside the grid?
넓혀야죠
Then we expand it.
누구 듣고 있나요? 도와주세요
Can anybody hear this? We need help.
- 응답바람. 테라 노바
- 접수했다. 여기는 탱고 노벰버 원
- Come in. Terra Nova. - Copy that. This is Tango November One.
신원을 밝혀라
Identify yourself.
테일러 중령님! 저 헌터 보이스예요
Commander Taylor! This is Hunter Boyce.
저, 저희 지금 수송차에 갇혔어요
구역 밖이에요
We-We're stuck in a rover outside the perimeter.
..수송차가 작동되니, 헌터?
..Is your rover operational,Hunter?
식서스가 우리 배터리를 빼 갔어요
Sixers jacked our power cells.
헌터, 들리니?
슬래셔. 다시 한 번 말해봐
Hunter,do you copy?
Slashers. Say that again.
슬래셔에 대해서 다시 말해봐
And say again about slashers.
- 탄약을 아껴야 해. 짧게 쏴
- 알았어
- Conserve your ammo.Short bursts.
- Got it.
헌터, 슬래셔에 대해 다시 한 번 말해봐라
Hunter,say again about slashers.
어, 세 마리, 더 많을지도 몰라요
Uh,three,maybe more.
아무것도 안 보여요.. 80m 정도..
I can't see any... ...about 80 meters down from...
80m라고?
80 meters?
- 우리가 동쪽으로 80m 정도에 있다고요
- 어디 동쪽?
- I said we're about 80 meters east...
- East of what?
- 어디 있지?
- 잡아! 조쉬, 무전기 잡아!
- Where is it?
- Grab it! Josh,grab the radio!
여보세요!
Hello! If you're still there,
- 우, 우린 대략 동쪽으로 80km에..
- 조쉬예요
- we're,we're about 80 kilometers east... - That's Josh.
조쉬?
Josh?
조쉬, 아빠다
Josh,it's your dad.
마지막 송신을 못 받았어
Could not copy last transmission.
다시 말해다오
Please repeat.
엄마! 아빠! 맞으세요?
Mom! Dad! Is that you?
들었니, 조쉬? 다시 말해줘
Do you copy,Josh? Please repeat.
조쉬!
Josh!
여긴 없어
Out of the way.
내 쪽은 깨끗해
My side's clear.
나도
Mine,too.
떠난 것 같아?
You think they left?
슬래셔에 대해선 아무것도 짐작 마
Don't assume anything with slashers.
우리가 총을 쏴서 잠시 피한 것뿐이야
Our gunfire drove them away for now,
다시 무리를 지어서 돌아오겠지
but they'll regroup and come back.
아니, 우리.. 우리 할 수 있을 때 도망치자
No,we should... we should make
a run for it while we still can.
- 대체 어디로?
- 테라 노바!
- Make a run for what?
- Terra Nova!
거기까지 5km야
태쉬, 우리 못 갈 거야
That's,like, five klicks away.
Tash,we'd never make it.
우린 무기도 있고, 뭐라도 하는 게
갇혀 있는 것보단 낫잖아
We have weapons, and anything is
better than being sitting ducks...
안 돼, 몇 마리나 있는지도 모르고
No,we don't know how many
of them are out there,
탄약이 한정돼 있다고
and we have limited ammunition.
잠깐, 새삼스럽겠지만
Hey,hey,hey, I might be a fresh,but,
중령님이 우리 조난 신호를 받았으니까
우리가 위험에 처한 것도 알 거야
I mean,Commander Taylor got our distress call.
Commander Taylor knows we're in trouble.
우릴 데리러 올 때까지
조금만 기다리면 돼
We just got to hold on a little
while longer for him to get here.
몇 시간이 걸릴 수도 있는 거잖아!
It could take them hours to find us!
슬래셔를 붙잡아둘 만큼의 탄약은 있어
버틸 수 있을 거야
Well,we have enough ammo to hold off the slashers
a little while longer.We can make it.
오, 젠장
자기가 무슨 말 하는지도 모르면서
My God,he doesn't even know
what he's talking about!
- 타샤, 타샤..
- 피 냄새를 맡을 거라고!
- Tasha,Tasha...
- They can smell his blood!
피 냄새를 맡을 거란 말이야!
They can smell his blood!
- 슬래셔들이 올 거야..
- 진정해!
- They're gonna come...
- Calm down!
- 살아남지 못할 거야!
- 타샤! 타샤!
- We're not gonna make it!
- Tasha! Tasha!
타샤, 안 돼!
Tasha,no!
- 타샤! 타샤!
- 그만해! 안 돼! 타샤! 자살행위야!
- Tasha! Tasha!
- Stop it! No! Tasha! It's suicide!
여기서 뭐 하세요?
What are you doing here?
이런 일이 생겨서
너희가 괜찮은지 보려고 왔어
Well,with everything going on,
I wanted to make sure you were okay.
네. 우린 괜찮아요
Yeah. You know,we're okay.
오빠한테 비하면요
Considering.
어, 수색팀한테 아직 연락은 없었지만
Uh,we haven't heard back
from the search team yet,
오래 걸리진 않을 거야
but,uh,shouldn't be long though.
네 오빠는 괜찮을 거라고 믿어
I'm sure your brother's gonna be okay.
- 뭐가 필요하면 말만..
- 가지 마요
- if you need anything,just...
- Don't go.
조이가 겁먹었어요
Uh,Zoe's scared.
그렇지, 조이?
Right,Zoe?
여기는 탱고 노벰버
모든 주파수를 열었다
This is Tango November.
I have all frequencies open.
헌터, 들리나?
Hunter, do you copy?
조쉬 섀넌, 들리니?
Josh Shannon, do you copy?
여긴 테일러 중령이다
계속 동쪽으로 가
This is Commander Taylor.
Just keep heading east
그쪽에서 신호가 온 것 같아
I think that's where
the signal originated.
이만한 기술력을 가졌으면
알아야 하는 거 아니야?
With all this technology,
shouldn't they know?
- 엘리자베스
- 다른 곳이라면 알았을 거요
Elisabeth. Anywhere else,we would know,
- 하지만 이렇게 빽빽한 정글에서라면..
- 조심해!
- but this is some dense jungle out...
- Watch out!
오, 세상에
Oh,God.
얘 이름이 뭐죠?
What's her name?
- 타샤요
- 그래, 타샤, 내 말 들리니?
- It's Tasha.
- Okay,Tasha, can you hear me?
나는 의사야, 알았지?
I'm a doctor,okay?
아빠 여다. 아빠야
I'm right here. It's me,Daddy.
아빠 여다, 아가야
I'm right here,honey.
이 상처를 지압해주세요
여기와 여기, 여기요
I need you to apply pressure
to this wound. Here,here,here.
타샤, 정신 차려봐, 응?
Tasha,you stay with me,okay?
슬래셔가 왔어요
총을 쐈는데..
Slashers came.
Fired the gun...
- 다른 애들이 어딨는지 말해줄 수 있겠니?
- 아니요
- Can you tell me where the others are?
- No.
빨리 안정시켜서 병원으로 후송해야겠어요
We'll get her safely to the
hospital as soon as I stabilize her.
타샤, 여기까지 오는데
물을 건너야 했니?
Tasha,did you have to go
through water to get here?
여기서 북쪽으로 반 킬로쯤에 개울이 있네
There's a stream about
a half a klick north of here.
브라코, 자넨 거즈와 박사 곁에 남아
Bracco,you stay here
with Guz and the doc.
알겠습니다
Yes,sir.
나머진 출발한다
Rest of you,gather up.
짐, 잠깐, 잠깐만
Jim,wait,wait.
저, 아까 내가 한 말은 미안해
Look,I-I'm sorry about
what I said before.
자기 잘못이 아니야
This is not your fault.
아니, 맞아
Yes,it is.
조쉬는 날 괴롭히려고
얘네랑 여기 온 거니까
Josh came out here with
these kids just to spite me.
괴롭혀? 걔는 당신을 꼭 닮았어
Spite you? No,he is you.
예쁜 여자애와 법칙을 어길 기회라면
Pretty girl and a chance to break the rules--
저 나이에 당신이 했을 법한 일이잖아
you'd have done the same thing at his age.
꼭 알아두라고
Well,you should know.
당신이 그 여자애였어
You were that girl.
꼭 데려와
Bring him back.
그럴게
I will.
맥스, 우리 수송차까지 뛰어가자
Max,say we make a run for our rover.
그 배터리들 쓸 수 있는 거지?
Are those power cells usable?
이건 완전히 방전됐어
This one's completely drained.
다른 거 두 개는 반씩 남았고
The other two are half charged.
만약 헌터랑 내가 엄호해주면
설치하는데 얼마나 걸리겠어?
If Hunter and I cover you, how fast do you
think you can get those power cells installed?
5분에서 10분쯤
Maybe five,ten minutes.
우리 수송차까지 뛰자
I say we make a run for our rover,
전원 켜고 벗어나는 거야
power it up and get the hell out of here.
헌터, 탄창 확인 좀 해줘
Hunter,check the
cylinders on our weapons.
우린 할 수 있어
We can do this, you guys.
가자
Come on.
다쳤니?
Are you hurt?
괜찮아
I'm fine.
통솔을 제법 잘하는 것 같다
You're pretty good at this
whole taking charge thing.
뭐, 아빠가 중령님 밑에 있던
상등병이셨거든
Yeah,well,my dad was a corporal
under Commander Taylor.
아빠한테 배운 건가 봐
I guess he kind of rubbed off on me.
셨다고?
Was?
신실릭 열병
Sincyllic fever.
엄마도야
Mom,too.
미안
Sorry.
모두 언젠가는 부모님을 잃게 돼
Everybody loses their
parents sooner or later.
그 반대가 되면 절대 안 되는 거지
What's not supposed to happen
is the other way around.
무사히 빠져나가자, 알았지?
Let's try to get the hell out
of here in one piece,all right?
슬래셔를 만나면 아랫배를 겨냥하게
If we do engage slashers,
aim for the underbelly.
가죽이 마취총으로 뚫기엔
너무 두꺼우니까
Hides are too thick for
the tranq-guns to penetrate.
꼬리에서 반드시 5미터 떨어지도록
Stay five meters clear of their tails.
탱고 노벰버, 여긴 거즈만
Tango November, this is Guzman. 탱고 노벰버, 여긴 거즈만
- 들리십니까? - 그래, 듣고 있다
- Do you copy? - Yeah,I'm here.
타샤를 데리고 캠프로 돌아갑니다
We're taking Tasha back to camp.
박사님이 수술해야 한답니다
Doc says she needs surgery.
알았다
Understood. 알았다
거즈, 잘 보호해 드리게
Hey,Guz, she's in good hands. 거즈, 잘 보호해 드리게
잘 지키겠습니다
미라가 중령님 근처에 있습니다
Keep sharp eyes. Mira's your area.
식서스의 무전통신을 들었습니다
We picked up Sixers' radio chatter. 식서스의 무전통신을 들었어요
빌어먹을! 알았다
Damnation! Copy that.
미라. 그걸 잡아버려야 해
Mira-- just what
I need right now.
그쪽 사람들은 항상
이렇게 말썽입니까?
Her people always this much trouble?
그래, 지금까지는
Yeah,so far.
누가 그들을 보냈는지
왜 보냈는지 모르지만
I don't know who sent them,
I don't know why,
내가 이대로 내버려두진 않아
but I'll tell you this
I'm not going to let them,
누가 됐든 우리 하는 일을
방해하게 두지는 않을 거네
I'm not going to let anybody stand in
the way of what we are building here.
테라 노바는 성공하게 될 거야
Terra Nova will succeed.
어때, 조쉬?
How's it looking,Josh?
우리 수송차까지 뛰기엔 안전해 보여
Looks like we've got a
clear run to the vehicle.
괜찮아, 이쪽은 깨끗해
Okay,I think we're clear on this side.
여기도야
This side, too.
좋아, 다들 붙어 있어야 해
All right,remember to stay together.
준비됐니?
We all set?
잠깐, 좋은 생각이 아닌 것 같아
Look,maybe this isn't such a good idea.
어쩌면.. 구하러 올 때까지
기다리는 게 나을지도 몰라
Maybe we... should just
stay here and wait for help.
이미 끝난 얘기잖아
여기 있을 수는 없어
We talked about this.
We can't stay here.
이봐 진정해
Just take it easy,man.
있지, 슬래셔는 아무나 물어뜯어
Look,if a slasher's going to munch on any of us,
네 앙상한 엉덩이만 무는 게 아니라고
it won't be your scrawny ass.
헌터!
Hunter!
헌터, 괜찮아?
Hunter, are you okay?
좀 도와줘
Give me a hand.
수송차 안에 들어가야만 해
We've got to get into the rover.
- 헌터는?
- 내가 남아서 엄호할게
- What about Hunter?
- I'll stay and cover him.
너희는 전원전지를 꼽고 차를 움직여
You guys just get those power
cells in and get the thing moving.
탄약이 떨어졌어!
I'm out!
이리 와
Come on.
옆구리에 마취총
Flank and tranq.
계속 와, 스카이. 엄호하고 있어
Keep coming,Skye. Got you covered.
- 조쉬!
- 아빠!
- Josh!
- Dad!
엎드려!
Get down!
괜찮아, 괜찮아. 아빠다
It's okay,it's okay.It's me.
다 끝났어
It's over.
차에 태워
Get him in the transport.
맥스. 맥스!
Max. Max!
오, 세상에
Oh,God.
괜찮을 거야
You're going to be okay.
넌 괜찮니, 어린 아가씨?
You all right, young lady?
타샤, 그, 그 애가 캠프로 갔어요
Tasha-- she-she tried
to make it back to camp.
우리가 발견했다
We got her.
식서스가 있었다고 했지?
You said there were Sixers?
네, 저쪽에요
Yeah,over there.
함께 가지
With me.
사라졌어요
He's gone.
미라야. 부하를 데리러 왔겠지
Mira. She came for her man.
자, 검사 좀 해보자
Let's get you looked at.
다친 다리에 너무 힘주지 마
Try not to put too much weight on it.
왜 슬래셔라고 하는지 이제 알겠지?
I guess we know why they
call them slashers,huh?
- 죄송해요
- 괜찮아
- I'm sorry.
- It's okay.
오늘 일은 정말 죄송하다고
말씀드리고 싶어요
I want to say how sorry
I am for what happened today.
안다
I know.
저희 부모님 돌아가신 후로
계속 잘해 주셔서..
You know,you've been so
good to me since my folks...
실망시켜 드리고 싶지 않아요
I just don't like to disappoint you.
사지가 멀쩡하게 돌아왔으니
그게 중요한 거지, 그렇지?
Well,you're still in one piece,
that's the important thing,huh?
거기가 왜 금지구역인지 이제 알았지?
Now you know why that area's off limits.
네?
Sir.
거긴 슬래셔 영역이란다
Well,it's slasher territory.
네, 그렇네요
Yeah,of course.
그래 어쨌든 거기서
뭘 하고 있었던 거지?
So just what were you all
doing out there,anyhow?
바보 같은 짓이죠
Dumb stuff.
술 마셨어요
Drinking.
폭포 근처에는 가지 않았지, 그렇지?
You didn't go anywhere
near the falls,did you?
안 갔어요
No,sir.
좋아, 잘했다
Good.Good.
위험한 물일 수도 있단다
Those can be some treacherous waters.
누군가 확실히 여기 왔었어요
발자국을 찾았거든요
Someone was definitely here.
Found footprints.
그 아이들이야
It was those kids.
테일러가 싫어할 텐데
Taylor's not going to like that.
이걸 감추고 싶어하잖아
He wants to keep all this under wraps.
왜 바위를 그냥 폭파시켜버리지 않죠?
Why doesn't he just
blast them off the rocks?
이게 아들과 연결된
하나 남은 고리니까
'Cause they're the only
connection he has left to his son.
아직도 그 망할 자식이
왜 여기 이러는지 모르겠어요
I still don't get why the crazy
bastard does this out here.
왜 인 것 같아?
Why do you think?
자기 아버지 앞에 던져놓는 거야
To throw it in his old man's face.
해답에 다가가면 다가갈수록
Every time he gets closer to an answer,
아버지 보라고 남겨놓는 거지
he puts it here for Taylor to see.
상기시키는 거야
테라 노바가 존재하는 진짜 이유를
To remind him-- the real reason
for Terra Nova's existence.
과거를 지배하고, 미래를 다스린다
Control the past, control the future.
이게 열쇠야.. 모든 것에 대한 열쇠
These are the key... to everything.
우리한테로 떨어질까?
Is it going to fall on us?
뭐가 떨어진다는 거야, 아가?
Is what going to fall on us,sweetie?
저게 뭐야?
What is it?
저건, 내 귀여운 조이, 달이란다
That,my little Zoe, is the moon.
우리에게 떨어지지 않을 거야
And no,it's not going to fall on us.
어떻게 생겼는지 잊어버릴 뻔했네
Almost forgot what it looks like.
내가 어렸을 땐 공기가 너무 나빠지면
볼 수가 없었거든
I was a kid when the air got so
bad you couldn't see it anymore.
항상 저렇게 컸어?
Was it always so big?
항상은 아니야
Not always.
매년 지구로부터 0.5cm씩 멀어진대
It moves about half a centimeter
away from the Earth every year.
그러니까 어제보다는 훨씬 가까워진 거지
So it's much closer
than it was yesterday.
내일이겠지
You mean tomorrow.
무슨 뜻인지 아시잖아요
You know what I mean.
하늘이 놀라워요
The sky is insane.
여기 모든 곳이 다 그렇지
This whole place is.
여긴 별들도 다 달라요
The stars are all different here,too.
2149년에 있던 자리가 아닌 거죠
They're not in the
same place as in 2149,
왜냐하면 우주가 8천5백만 년 적게
확장했으니까요
because the universe has had
85 million fewer years to expand.
한 번 계산해 보세요
I mean,do the math.
계산은 너한테 맡기마, 딸아
We'll just leave the
math up to you,sweetie.
번역수정
박창균(fasces@paran.com)
한글교정
정규은(jgeun1007@naver.com)
자막제작 - ND24 클럽 자막팀
(http://cafe.naver.com/nd24club)
조건부 배포 / 수정금지
배포시 자막 출처를 꼭 밝혀주세요